Robert Chambers collection on William Wagner and the History of the Wagner Free Institute of Science, 1798-1980 (bulk 1820-1910) WFIS.90-015
Wagner Free Institute of Science
- Wagner Free Institute of Science records, Series 4
  - Financial Records
    - Reports of the Auditing Committee, 1901, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Letter from Harrison S. Morrison turning down position on Finance Committee, 1904 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Checks and Statements of rental property payments of Estate of William Wagner from J.G. Rothermel (five folders), 1911-1915 (Box 4, Folder 41-45)
    - Correspondence to and from Samuel Wagner and John Rothermel regarding properties and financial statements, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Expenditures and Income, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - List of revised estimates, undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Instruction
    - Ticket for complimentary Fall Course at the Wagner Free Institute of Science, 1874 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Letter from Joseph Leidy to Thomas Montgomery regarding joining the faculty, 1888 October 6 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Drawing for a medal awarded to William H. Dall for his "investigations and writings in Paleontology", 1889 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence from Imogene Chandler to Thomas Montgomery regarding literary lectures, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence regarding and announcements of courses for University Extension, 1900-1905 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1900-1901 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Description of the Wagner Free Institute of Science's educational programs (written by William Wagner?), undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Publications
    - Letters from Joseph Leidy regarding writing preface for first issue of Transactions and other Transactions issues, 1886, 1889 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence regarding Transactions, including letters from William H. Dall of the Smithsonian Institute to Joseph Willcox and Joseph Leidy, from Joseph Leidy to Samuel Wagner, and W.S. Yeats of the Smithsonian Institute to Joseph Willcox, 1887-1890 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence regarding Volume III of Transactions, 1888-1895 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence from William H. Dall of the Smithsonian Institute to Joseph Willcox regarding Transactions, 1891-1893 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence and Lists of foreign and American addresses for "Professor Dall's paper," which was probably published in Transactions, 1892 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence with the Albertype Company regarding printing plates, 1893 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence to and from Thomas Montgomery, Joseph Leidy and Joseph Willcox regarding Medial Lertiary, by Conrad, 1893 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence regarding plates for Joseph Leidy's paper in Transactions, 1894-1895 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence from the Cleveland Public Library and J.P. Lippincott Company regarding book binding and paper samples, 1896-1897 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence to and from M.B. Clarke, Joseph Willcox, F.A. Lucas, Thomas Montgomery, N. H. Winchell, and William Dall, 1900-1901 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence from Amadeus Graham to C. Johnson regarding illustrations, 1901 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence from Ralph Arnold to Thomas Montgomery regarding monograph on California Pectin, 1901 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Library
    - Letters from the Boston Society of Natural History to William Wagner regarding outstanding fees for books purchased, 1841 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Librarian's Reports, 1899 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Librarian's Reports, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Committee on Library Report, 1900 March 7 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Letters from the Library of Congress and the Smithsonian Institution regarding periodicals, 1900-1901 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Librarian's Reports, 1901 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Letters from E. Lybrand to the Board in support of the Library and Mrs. Eastman, 1901 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence with Robert Chambers, Director, regarding the Wagner Free Institute of Science's historical library collections, 1967-1980 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - List of materials received from and sent to the Mercantile Library, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Lists, bills and receipts for books and William Wagner's printed request for books for the library of the Wagner Free Institute of Science, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Museum
    - Correspondence regarding specimens, including letters from William Wagner to William Dixon, Dr. Eberle, Samuel Wagner and J. Rogers, President of the Board of Admiralty, P.J. Roding; and P.J. Hoffman; and from V. Tineo to William Wagner, 1814-1889 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence regarding collections, including letters from B. Silliman, T.A. Conrad, S.G. Morton (of note is the correspondence between B. Silliman and William Wagner regarding the publication of William Wagner's paper on a new species of fossils, which had been previously described by others), 1839-1840 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Receipt for shells purchased from dealer L. Purreyss in Vienna, 1841 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Letters from Joseph Leidy to Wagner regarding the mineralogical cabinet and fossil remains of the camerasaurus at the museum and other specimens, 1886-1891 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Letters from Joseph Leidy to Samuel Wagner regarding Wagner Free Institute of Sciences collection of Florida fossils, 1887 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Geological Memorandum--Maryland, Virginia and North Carolina, made by Joseph Willcox, 1889 November (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Expenses, Correspondence and Report regarding Joseph Willcox's trip to North Carolina, 1891 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence regarding borrowing specimens from the College of Physicians, purchasing specimen jars, and other museum matters, 1891-1892 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence regarding acquisition of specimens, descriptions of curator positions and additions to the By-laws, 1892 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence regarding estimates for and photographs of crocodiles, 1892 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence regarding specimen loans, 1894-1901 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Annual Report for the Museum, 1899 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Museum Reports, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Report on the Needs of the Museum, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence from Thomas Montgomery to the Board regarding a guidebook and railing around the gallery, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Museum Reports, 1901 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence regarding Charles Johnson working with the Academy of Natural Sciences, 1901 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Resignation letter of Charles Johnson as curator, 1903 January 19 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Sketches of specimens, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)